SERGIU GHENCIU

Software Engineer

About me

1024gs@gmail.com

+44 7454 026160

London, UK

10+ years of IT experience. I have got strong technical knowledge of JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, RESTful APIs, etc. I am creative, passionate, eager, and excited about what I do. I like new challenges on a daily basis and I enjoy my job since I have something new to learn each day about the latest programs and technologies in a rapidly changing environment.

https://rubymage.github.io

Personal skills







Languages

- Romanian: Native proficiency

- English: Professional working proficiency

- French: Willing to learn

Social

Good communication skills and flexibility in any circumstance, persevering, energetic, creative, team work abilities, leadership skills, resistant to stress

Fast learner

The ability to easily understand and learn fast, most of what has to deal with the digital world. Usually spending my personal time in learning new technologies and keeping up with the industry trends

https://rubymage.github.io 2/7

Experience

Front End Engineer/Pod Lead

Masabi - London, UK

June 2021 - Present

Worked on a cross-platform white-label app. Worked with different teams to gather the requirements and migrated some of the most important features to the new codebase. I then was given the Pod Lead role, completed the migration and delivered a new feature. I also worked with people and learned what were the challenges they faced regarding the release process and provided a solution on how we can continuously deliver a white-label app.

Tools and technologies:

Angular, TypeScript, RxJs, Ionic, Capacitor, Cordova, iOS, Android, Jasmine, Jest, Nodejs, Bamboo Server, Swift, Objective C, Java

Staff Front End Engineer

Artfinder - London, UK

July 2020 - Feb 2021

Designed and implemented the development environment for the frontend (monolithic-to-microservices migration). I then migrated the artist and product pages to react while significantly improved the performance of the pages. In parallel I helped interview people and build the tech team.

Achievements:

- Developed a proxy server that allowed me to develop the FE under any domain name while pointing to any API environment
- Designed and implemented an API mock system that allowed me to speed up the development and also to easily achieve a test coverage of 70%
- Migrated artist and product pages to react
- Increased the Performance from a score of 44 to 96
- Increased the Accessibility from a score of 80 to 97

https://rubymage.github.io

- Increased the Best practices from a score of 64 to 79 (third-party libs drag it down)
- Increased the SEO from a score of 75 to 91

Tools and technologies:

NextJs, React, TypeScript, Jest, Enzyme, Bootstrap, Python, Foundation 5, VueJS

Senior Front End Engineer

Simply Business - London, UK

Dec 2019 - 2020

Main responsibilities:

- Worked with cross functional teams
- Developed AB tests
- Participated in discovery meeting providing technical support

Achievements:

- Developed the unified-qcp AB test

Senior Front End Engineer

Amalytics LTD - London, UK

May 2017 - 2019

Main responsibilities:

- Collaborated with all areas of the business including the BA team
- Ensured the technical feasibility
- Estimated the stories and contributed to the Road Map
- Decided which tools and technologies to use
- Designed and ensured the correct development and implementation of the application's modules
- Coordinated the frontend team in order to produce clean, maintainable and scalable code
- Ensured high performance on mobile and desktop
- Contributed on backend side especially designing the REST APIs

Achievements:

- Migrated the application onto the second version of the API
- Delivered CostLens, Remove Scenario and Migrate Scenario Modules

https://rubymage.github.io 4/7

- Improved the appearance and responsiveness across all devices
- Improved the code quality by implementing ESLint and PrettierJS
- Decreased the build size from 664KB down to 257KB
- Reduced the deployment time from 5 minutes down to 24 seconds

Tools and technologies:

Functional Programming, React, TypeScript, Ramda, D3.js, Jest, Enzyme, Materializecss, SASS, Autoprefixer, Prettier, ESLint, Webpack, Docker, RESTful API, JavaScript, VanillaJS, AngularJS, ES2015, ES6, ES7, NPM, Babel, RollupJs, Polyfill, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Material Design, GIT

Full Stack JavaScript Engineer

Winify AG - Chisinau, Moldova

Mar 2013 - 2016

Main responsibilities:

- Produced neat code according to software requirements
- Designed and developed RESTful APIs
- Integrated with third party applications and services
- Designed and developed intuitive, responsive and visually appealing user interfaces
- Ensured high performance on mobile and desktop

Tools and technologies:

MongoDB, Express.js, AngularJS, Node.js, Karma, Jasmine, Mocha, Chai, Elasticsearch, jQuery, Anime.js, Bootstrap, Materializecss, OAuth 2.0, Common third-party APIs, RESTful API, JavaScript, VanillaJS, ES2015, ES6, Material Design, NPM, Gulp.js, Babel, Webpack, LiveReload, ESLint, Useref, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Autoprefixer, Polyfill, GIT

Web Developer

Casgon LTD - Chisinau, Moldova

Mar 2010 - 2013

Main responsibilities:

- Designed and developed the application including the backend
- Designed the database
- Tested and verified links and functionality
- Installed and configured the web server

https://rubymage.github.io 5/7

- Deployed the application
- Increased traffic to the website via SEO
- Automated the deployment process

Tools and technologies:

JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, MySQL, GIT, Apache, Nginx, UNIX

Network Administrator

Gigabyte Computers LTD - Chisinau, Moldova

Dec 2005 - 2009

Main responsibilities:

- Designed and implemented networks
- Installed and configured devices
- Diagnosed and troubleshot issues
- Controlled access to services

Education

Master's Degree in Computer Science, Information Technology

Technical University of Moldova

2014 - 2016

Bachelor's Degree in Economics, Business Management

Academy of Economic Studies of Moldova

2003 - 2007

Baccalaureate Degree

Theoretical Lyceum, Sciences

2000 - 2003

https://rubymage.github.io 6/7

Sergiu Ghenciu - 1024gs@gmail.com - +44 7454 026160

https://rubymage.github.io 7/7